Contact

amattson84@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/aimeemattson (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Business Project Management Supply Chain

Aimee Mattson

Wholesale Professional Portland

Summary

I am a business professional who is highly qualified and able to produce results in various office settings. My nine years of experience allows me to contribute to the overall success of the business by being highly effective and efficient.

Experience

US Distributing
Administrator and Accounts Receivable Specialist
July 2014 - July 2019 (5 years 1 month)
Portland, Oregon Area

Conducted analysis and recommendations regarding sales performance, efficiencies and productivity

for a \$10 million a year sales volume.

• Worked with a 20 (+) member sales team members to maintain sales metrics, monthly/yearly goals

and territory increases.

 Worked as a key member of a special projects team that oversaw annual company trade show

resulting in over \$3 million dollars annually. Managed staff and customer logistics and accommodations

for 350+ people. Worked with event site staff and team to coordinate and plan banquet event orders.

Worked with executive team to create event itinerary and event banquet menu. Worked with vendors to set up booth areas and sales

materials. Over saw post trade show analytics, sales analytics and customer reviews.

- Managed accounts receivable department. General bookkeeping duties.
 Over saw daily, weekly and month end processes. Worked with corporate office to streamline accounting processes.
- Monitored AR aging balances and light duty collections.. Managed daily deposits and reconciliations. Worked with clients to develop

repayment plans. Company expense reports and reconciliations.

Worked with Purchasing department on daily sales trends and analytics.
 Monitored daily margin

reports. Evaluated inventory exceptions related to sales transactions.

 Helped prepare internal reports and memos to sales team and staff. Helped to facilitate day-to-day

communications within the organization and between clients. Served as gatekeeper and acted as a gateway for the executive team in both internal and external environments.

 Helped create, execute and maintain marketing strategy. Created marketing materials via Adobe Photoshop. Used external programs such as Constant contact to do mass email marketing to clients. Worked with executive team to create in house campaigns.

Great Western Ink Purchasing Manager 2013 - 2014 (1 year)

- Managed and coordinated \$675,000 worth of rotating inventory, raw materials and consignment items.
- Developed and implemented standard operating procedures for 5 branch locations.
- Reduced the cost of goods purchased without causing stock outs and loss of sales.
- Organized push of sales for slow moving inventory and reduced slow moving inventory by 12%.

- Prepared purchase orders and verified receipt of items received.
- Provided purchase planning and control information to Operations Manager by collecting, analyzing, and summarizing data and trends.
- Assisted Supply Chain Management with manufacturing procedures and helped track budget expenses.

Production Media, Inc.

Executive Assistant and Production Manager June 2011 - August 2013 (2 years 3 months)

Prepared, proofread and administered requested documents.

Compiled requested data for board meetings and recorded meeting minutes.

Coordinated executives schedule by arranging meetings, conferences and travel arrangements.

Managed office administration and assisted HR, A/P & A/R departments.

Developed and implemented standard operating procedures.

As Production Manger; directed promotional campaigns and production of products sold.

increased turnover rate of goods sold and delivered.

Managed all departments that contributed to the production and distribution of media sold.

Represented company at regional trade shows to promote products and acquire new clients.

Empire Stone Company
Executive Management Assistant
February 2006 - June 2008 (2 years 5 months)
Bend, Oregon Area

Directed and facilitated office administration.

Coordinated with sales force and assisted in the sales department.

Assisted General Manager to increase sales profits and streamline efficiency of business.

Continued education and training to be meet compliance standards for OSHA and HIPAA laws.

Prepared, proofread and administered requested documents.

Compiled requested data for board meetings and recorded meeting minutes.

Coordinated executives schedule by arranging meetings, conferences and travel arrangements.

Managed office administration and assisted HR, A/P & A/R departments.

Developed and implemented standard operating procedures.

Education

Portland State University · (2014 - 2016)

Southern Oregon University
Associate of Arts (AA), Dentistry · (2003 - 2004)